Paul Campbell - Curriculum Vitae

19 Moorland Close, Moortown, Leeds, West Yorkshire LS17 6JR phone: 07530 611852 email:paulgcampbell@gmail.com web: www.decoratedworld.co.uk/

Statement

Knowledgeable and enthusiastic Lead Web Developer/Architect with nine years wide-ranging experience in IT with a special focus on Internet technologies. Extensive experience in the development, implementation and management of high volume, evolving, live web applications and the management of technical teams throughout project lifecycle.

I am passionate about turning complex or time consuming tasks into simple, intuitive and accessible applications which empower users to get their jobs done.

Skills Summary

Skill Type	Skills accrued
Technical	.NET (1-4), c#, Visual Studio (2003-2010), MVC, WCF, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript (jQuery, Backbone etc), Nant, Rake, RSpec, nUnit, ORMs (Fluent nHibernate, SubSonic, Linq-SQL, ActiveRecord), Java (Android), MS SQL, NoSQL (db4o / Mongo), Security (XSS, XSRF, SQL injection, Network analysis), XML, XSLT, CI, IoC, TDD, BDD, DDD, REST, SOAP, Git, TFS, Subversion, Mono
Graphics	Adobe Photoshop, Image Ready; Lightwave, Fireworks
Various / Methodologies	Domain modelling Understanding of Agile Methodologies Kanban / Lean Able to prioritise work in order to meet deadlines Team leading and co-ordination with ability to work as an effective team member Able to develop and critically evaluate ideas, business policies and processes Strong presentation and mentoring skills

Work Experience

09/2011 - Present: Lead Developer / Architect - Decorated World Ltd Consulting for various organisations in Lead Developer / Architect role.

02/2011 - 09/2011: Software Architect - StarCompliance

Providing design guidance and consultancy for development of financial software for use by investment banks. Lead the design and development for migration of enterprise compliance software from ASP.NET to REST based architecture with MS MVC & JS clients. Introduce Continuous Integration, TDD / BDD methodologies to dev team.

Technologies/Tools/Methodologies utilised

.net 4, c#, Visual Studio 2010, MS MVC 3, Razor, jQuery, nHibernate 3.1, NHProf, REST, nUnit, Rhino Mocks / nSubstitue, IIS, MS SQL 2008, TFS, VS 2010 with ReSharper, TDD, BDD, Continuous Integration, Kanban

12/2006 – 02/2011: Lead Web Developer - Consumer Credit Counselling Service Building web based financial software for use by high street banks, creditors and the public for the debt industry. Integrating in house systems with creditor, banking and other third party systems.

Responsibilities include:

Lead the development of high quality software solutions based on specifications provided by analysts. Responsible for technical design decisions affecting projects.

Responsible for the day to day supervision of development team members.

Analyse functional requirements in order to progress new developments and support work.

Train and mentor Web Developers to ensure consistent, high quality work is produced.

Peer review work produced within the Project Development Team.

Co-ordinate deployment of software releases.

Provide technical consultation and guidance for Analysis and Testing team.

Proactively stay abreast of emerging technologies and provide onward communication.

Review of security of web applications and implement security best practises.

Technologies/Tools utilised

.net 1.1 / 2 / 3.5, c#, vb.net, Visual Studio 2003 - 2008, MS MVC 1-3, WCF, LINQ, Web Forms, Ruby, Rake, jQuery, nUnit, Moq, Watin, Cruise Control, nAnt, nHibernate, NHProf, Custom ORM, SOAP, REST, IIS, MS SQL (2000 – 2008), Team Foundation Server, VS 2008, TestDriven.Net

08/2005 - 12/2006: Senior Web Developer - Direct Golf UK

www.direct-golf.co.uk is the second busiest golf website in the country (Hitwise Category: Sports-Golf), receiving over 100,000 visitors a week and turning over tens of thousands of pounds of golf equipment each day. During my time at Direct Golf, and directly related to my work, the website won various awards including:

Best Transactional Website – 2005 ECMOD Awards Best Online Retailer – Golf Punk Magazine

Design and development lead for Britain's second busiest sports e-commerce website. SEO and email marketing for e-commerce and product sites. Requirements gathering for internal systems. Design and development of internal systems. Mentor junior developers.

Technologies utilised

VS2005, .net 1.1 / 2, Web Forms, SQL 2000, MS AJAX, Scriptaculous, SubSonic, SubVersion

07/2004- 08/2005: Independent IT and Internet Consultant – Variety of clients Build and maintenance of web applications and SEO for various B2B and B2C web sites.

Technologies utilised include: HTML, ASP.NET (VB.NET), ASP, VBScript, JavaScript, MS SQL 2000, CSS, Visual Studio 2003, DreamWeaver, Flash, Photoshop.

03/2003 - 07/2004: IT Administrator / Web Developer - AEC UK Ltd

Duties included:

Design and development of company websites, and taking control of promotion, e-newsletters and web marketing. I was successful in gaining top ten search engine results for the relevant search phrases for the websites. Design and implementation of the company intranet, and development of several applications for building, logging and reporting quotes and keeping track of maintenance contracts. Design and implementation of a new network, upgrading the old NT 4 server, to a newer Windows 2000 Server with Active Directory.

12/2002 - 02/2003: Contract Multimedia Developer - Evolution Interactive Multimedia Design Agency based in Beverley, Yorkshire.

Duties included: Making amendments and updates to multimedia presentations Developing a multimedia learning aid for medical students in Flash Producing animations for various learning aids and presentations

Professional Qualifications / Training

Title	Course Provider	Date

How to design amazing web app user interfaces with Ryan Singer of 37Signals		April 2009
MS2784A - Tuning and optimising queries using MS SQL Server 2005	Remarc	December 2008
Certified Ethical Hacking	EC Council	November 2008
MS 2073B Programming a MS SQL Database	Remarc	September 2007
MS 2310 - Developing Microsoft ASP.NET Web Applications using Visual Studio .NET	Remarc	January 2007

Education

Establishment	Date	Qualification
	1998 - 2002	BSc (Hons) 2:1
Main areas studied: Java, Web		
development, Flash, Photoshop,		
Multimedia development		
New College Swindon	1998	3 A-Levels
Physics, Maths, Psychology		

Personal Interests

I am a keen kite boarder and skier. I enjoy both listening to and playing music. I try to get to as many gigs and festivals as my time allows. I play guitar, ukulele and am learning the banjo.

References

Tim Ward	CTO, Star Compliance	tim.ward@starcompliance.com	0190 4623846
Mark Robinson	Development Team Manager, CCCS	markro@cccs.co.uk	0113 235 5336
Neil Rowett	Web manager, Direct Golf UK Ltd	neil.rowett@direct-golf.co.uk	0800 0139139